André Gonçalves

Lisbon, Portugal | +351 963 965 544 | andgcv@gmail.com andgcv.com | linkedin.com/in/andgcv | github.com/andgcv

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with experience in employing Java, MongoDB, Docker, Jenkins and Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) to create and deploy RESTful APIs and backend microservices, as well as React and JavaScript for dynamic frontend views, while following current Agile methodologies (Scrum) in my everyday role at work.

My communication, teamwork, and leadership skills often create an environment of joy and openness, which allows for effortless collaboration and the transfer of knowledge, technical or otherwise, within the team.

EDUCATION

ISTEC, LISBON

B.Eng IN MULTIMEDIA ENGINEERING Graduated Jul 2019 | Lisbon, PT Final Grade: 16 / 20

ISTEC, LISBON

AAS IN MULTIMEDIA PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT Graduated Jul 2017 | Lisbon, PT Final Grade: 15 / 20

COURSEWORK

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING

Web Application Development Database Management Systems and SQL Mobile Application Development JavaScript, SQL, Java, Python, C#, PHP, Swift UI/UX Design

A. APPLIED SCIENCE

Data Structures, Algorithms, and Complexity Analysis Networks and Data Communication Database Management

Project Management HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Java, C++

SKILLS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient with:

Agile (Scrum) • Jenkins • Docker • Java • JUnit MongoDB (NoSQL) • Microservices • REST Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) • Git Familiar with:

Python • JavaScript (ES6) • Node.js • React MySQL (SQL) • Linux

SOFT SKILLS

Strong:

Bilingual Communicator (English, Portuguese) Analytical and Goal-Oriented Mind • Initiative Learning Spirit • Critical Thinking

WORK EXPERIENCE

CRITICAL TECHWORKS | BMW GROUP

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CRITICAL RETAIL INTEGRATION SERVICES Dec 2020 - Present | Lisbon, PT

- Eliminated frequent downtimes experienced by our services by driving the Proof of Concept and implementation of a new Azure Application Gateway load balacing solution for newly created AKS clusters.
- Improved our API debugging and performance assessment processes by creating and deploying mock services which mimic third-party solutions' input and output.
- Constant participation in the development of cross-departmental integration projects and cooperation with external partners for production incident-handling.

VITAMIMOS

PHOTOGRAPHER, VIDEOGRAPHER AND GRAPHIC DESIGNER INTERN Feb 2017 - Aug 2017 | Carcavelos, Cascais, PT

- Photographed and filmed various entrepreneurship and nutrition-centered events, and took care of post-production of the photos and videos.
- Photograph published through one of Portugal's most renowned magazines, Time Out (Lisbon), in the "O Guia dos Miúdos 2017" (The Kids' Guide 2017) edition in June 2017, and the "Escapadinhas de Verão" (Summer Getaways) edition in July 2017.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

PY TRACE IMAGE - WIP | GITHUB

Summer 2022 - Present | Lisbon, PT

- Scripts for loading and preprocessing images, finding edges and drawing lines based on Canny edge detection.
- Created with Python OpenCV, NumPy, Matplotlib.

INNOVATHON 2019 | SUSTAINABILITY TECH MARATHON Summer 2019 | Cascais, PT

- 24-hour-long technology marathon, created by CEiiA, in Portugal, for the conceptualization of sustainability projects.
- Provided viable, innovative conceptual solutions based on the quantification, valorization, and transaction of data, employing Artificial Intelligence and Computer Vision as a way to identify and alert of residual waste within the oceans.